本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：冰蓝 Michael Reginamoon CS小明漫画家
翻译：Silence 迷失_绽放 箭头章鱼X 圈圈
时间轴：芒果树叶 大鲧治水 dreamdragon   后期：MythCreator
校对：Michael Reginamoon 小萝莉  总监:  苹果果
t(0,0,\\c&H000001&\t(500,4000,\c&H4D4E4F&)绿箭
t(0,0,\\c&H000001&\t(500,4000,\c&H4D4E4F&)第三季  第一集
《绿箭》上季回顾
Last season on "Arrow"...
这座城市仍然需要拯救
This city still needs saving.
不由兜帽男
Not by the hood.
需要一个英雄
It needs a hero.
如果你通过了严酷的考验  你会因此而强大
If you survive a crucible, you grow the stronger for it.
这个可以作为提醒
This is to remind you of that.
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard.
莎拉对刺客联盟宣誓了忠诚
Sara swore her allegiance to the League of Assassins.
-你答应要回去  -她会没事的
- You agreed to go back.? - She'll be ok.
我知道她没事
Yeah, I know she'll be ok,
但我担心的就是她哪方面没事
but ok what is what bothers me.
爸爸  爸爸
Dad? Dad!
斯莱德的整个计划就是要夺走我的一切  他做到了
Slade's whole plan was to take everything from me. He did.
斯莱德把劳蕾尔抓去
Slade took Laurel
因为他要杀掉我心爱的女人
because he wants to kill the woman I love.
-所以呢  -所以他抓错人了
- So? - So he took the wrong woman.
我爱你  你明白吗
I love you. Do you understand?
过去的五年里
The five years that I was gone,
我并非一直待在岛上
I wasn't always on the island.
我是阿曼达·沃勒  奎恩先生
My name is Amanda Waller., Mr. Queen.
欢迎来香港
Welcome to Hong Kong.
找到他了  在52号街  往东走
Got him. Coming up 52nd Streeet, heading east.
明白  还是说收到
Copy that. Or is it roger?
我从来都不知道区别
I never know the difference.
约翰  有一批装载非法火箭筒的车辆
John, there's an illegal shipment of rpgs
往你的方向开去
headed your way.
收到  我这就去
Roger. I'm on it.
所以的确是收到
Oh, so it is roger.
火箭筒安全  我看到了
Rpgs are secure. I've got eyes on.
罗伊
Roy!
我们去找你
We're coming to you.
文森特·斯蒂尔格雷夫
Vincent Steelgrave...
你辜负了这座城市
You have failed this city.
危险  禁止进入
绿箭刚除掉了另一个
The Arrow just took down another one
城市头号通缉犯
of the city's most wanted,
无可否认  过去五个月里
and there's no denying that the city's crime rate
城市的犯罪率直线下降
has plummeted in the past five months.
-不客气  -而且失业率下降
- You're welcome. - But so has its unemployment rate
人口减少
and its population.
到目前为止  我们经历了两次恐怖袭击
We have experienced two terrorist attacks in as many years.
星城即将死去  满是罪犯的监狱...
Starling City is dying, and a prison full of criminals--
又干掉一个
Take another off the board.
我们保持如此  星城
We keep this up, there will only be
就会只剩两种罪犯了
two types of criminals left in Starling City--
我们绳之以法的
the ones we put away
和闻风奔命的
and the ones that are running scared.
那是什么
What's that?
蕨类植物  它靠光线生长
A fern. It thrives on the light.
我想既然你现在住在这里了
I thought since you were living here now,
这地方可以美化一下
the place could do with a little sprucing.
我是让你给我买张床
I let you buy me a bed.
你睡在地板上
You were sleeping on the floor.
西娅又来短信了
Another text from Thea.
她现在在哪里
Where is she now?
阿马尔菲海岸
Amalfi Coast.
我一直让她发照片过来
I keep telling her to send photos.
我要出去巡逻  清醒一下
I'm going to go do a patrol, clear my head.
你今晚表现很棒
You did really good tonight.
我也要出去了
I'm going to head out, too.
我今天得上早班
I have to pull an early shift at work today,
这可能是  也可能不是我说过的最令人沮丧的话
which may or may not be the most depressing thing I've ever said.
明晚我们还继续吧
But we're still on for tomorrow night?
绝对的  我要把你变成
Absolutely. I am going to turn you
公司的主宰
into corporate master of the universe.
那些董事会成员肯定会恳求
Those board members are going to be begging
把奎恩联合企业卖给你和你的支持者
to sell Queen Consolidated back to you and your backers.
我也要走了
I'm going to roll out, too.
莱拉让我努力做那个麻烦的摇篮
Lyla has me trying to build the bassinet from hell.
那提醒了我...
That reminds me...
我想着既然你和莱拉有了女儿...
I figured since you and Lyla are having a girl...
你买不起的
Man, you cannot afford this.
我什么都买不起  所以我才亲手做了
I can't afford anything, which is why I made it.
箭头  我能做的为数不多的几样东西之一
Arrowheads, one of the few things that I can make.
很漂亮  谢谢
Well, it's beautiful. Thank you.
恭喜  约翰
Congratulations, John.
不仅仅是因为孩子
And not just on the baby.
你和莱拉很快乐
You and Lyla are happy.
你有空也该试试
Well, you know, you should try it some time.
前任加入了刺客联盟
Last girlfriend, she's in the League of Assassins.
上上任开枪打了上上上任
My girlfriend before that, she shot my girlfriend before that.
我目前可不怎么讨人喜欢
I'm not...not exactly a catch at the moment.
也许费利西蒂会改变那一切
Maybe Felicity will change all that.
现在不合适
It's...it's not the right time.
现在就是合适的时机  奥利弗
Things are as good now as ever will be, Oliver.
而且你爱她
And you love her.
你甚至都跟她说了
You even told her so.
我那是想骗斯莱德
I was trying to fool Slade.
是啊
Yes.
只不过现在你唯一骗的就是自己
Except now the only person you're fooling is yourself.
再次感谢
Thanks again.
五年前
妈妈  我还活着
我在香港
我跟你说了  我不说中文
I told you, I don't speak Chinese!
我也跟你说了  你再想着逃跑
And I told you, you try to escape again,
我就打晕你
I beat you senseless.
狱政局
斯蒂尔格雷请求判十五至二十年
Steelgrave took a plea for 15 to 20.
星城法院
在我把绿箭收集的证据亮出来以后
His lawyer folded like a deck chair
他的律师就萎靡不振了
after I hit him with the evidence that the Arrow gathered.
干得好
Good work.
你负责抓人  我负责治他们
You catch 'em, I cook 'em.
我是不是说得太大声了
Did I say that too loud?
没有
No, you're fine.
你有想过我们会合作吗
Did you ever think that we'd end up as business partners?
这就是你邀请我来的原因吗  劳蕾尔
Is that why you invited me down here, Laurel?
亲眼看着斯蒂尔格雷被送去坐牢
To see Mr. Steelgrave sent off into his new life?
不是
No.
我要给你个惊喜
I have a surprise for you.
你爸爸在这干什么
What's your dad doing here?
一会你就知道了
You'll see.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
老爸
Dad.
你怎么样
How are you?
要是他们告诉我升职要开新闻发布会
Well, if they had told me press conferences came with a promotion,
那我宁愿还是挨一枪
I would tell them I prefer getting shot at.
好在你的医生没有给你选择
Good thing your doctors didn't give you a choice, then.
虽然你很高兴我再也不能出外勤了
You know, you could try to hide the fact
但至少也该掩饰一下
that you're glad I can't get out in the field anymore.
令我高兴的是你安然无恙
I can't hide that I'm glad that you're safe.
-这是怎么回事  -这是给你的惊喜
- What's all this? - Your surprise.
谢谢大家  谢谢你们能来
Thank you all, thank you for coming.
五个月前  这个城市陷入危机
Five months ago, this city was under siege.
星城的警察们团结在兜帽男周围
And the SCPD rallied behind a man in a hood.
现在我升为了警监
Well, I ended up with a captain's rank,
而他连一句谢谢都没有得到
and he didn't even get a thank you.
但今天  他会受到感谢
But today, he does.
因为今天星城警局正式承认
'Cause today, the Starling City Police Department
这个被称为绿箭的人的合法身份
is formally recognizing the individual known as the Arrow.
并且我以我的新职位宣布
And I'm using my new position
解散
to disband
负责抓捕治安维护者的小组
the Anti-vigilante Task Force charged with capturing him.
谢谢
Thank you.
但不要误会  我们不会纵容私自执法
Now make no mistake-- vigilantism will never be tolerated.
但我拒绝以城市的名义追捕
But I refuse to hunt, in the name of this city,
法院广场现场直播
-这位拯救了城市的英雄  -把这玩意关掉
- the hero who saved it. - Shut that crap off.
他们不抓绿箭意味着要抓我们了
Less heat on the Arrow means more heat on us.
烟酒和火器管理局扣了我们的榴弹发射器
And the ATF now has our shipment of grenade launchers.
他们已经把我们的货截了
They got our shipment already?
那我们还向警察行贿干什么
What are we paying bribes to the cops for?
我们还有一个更紧迫的问题
We have a more pressing concern.
缺乏领导
Lack of leadership.
我举荐我自己  有反对的吗
I nominate myself. Any objections?
是的  不少
Yeah, a few.
那你说说吧
Illuminate me.
从哪开始  不光是因为你说话好笑
Where do I start? It's not just that you talk funny.
你根本就不会做生意
You don't know the first thing about business.
你只是个街头卖毒品的小混混
You're just a low level street dealer, a pill pusher.
我卖的那些毒品
Those pills I push?
名字叫"迷魂"
Are known as Vertigo.
我仿效"伯爵"
In the wake of the Count,
修改了一下他的配方
I tinkered some with his formula,
添加了某种蘑菇产出的添加剂
introduced an additive produced by certain mushrooms.
我造的"迷魂"让你看到你最害怕的形象
My Vertigo reveals the face of your greatest fear.
我刚才说了
As I was saying...
你们缺乏领导  我举荐我自己
lack of leadership. I nominate myself.
有反对的吗
Any objections?
我们的做法简单明了
Our course of action is straight as an arrow.
先生们
Gentlemen...
我们要杀了绿箭
we're going to kill him.
威登酒吧
工作得怎么样
How was work?
那不是工作  那简直是折磨自己的灵魂
"It" is not work. It is a soul crushing exercise in misery
出卖健康  简单来说
that offers health and dental. Suffice it to say,
我非常积极地
I am highly motivated
说服董事会把公司卖回给你
to help convince the board to sell you back the company.
但不幸的是  你不够资格
Unfortunately, you don't really have
来管理奎恩联合企业
the qualifications to run Queen Consolidated,
不过你有激情
But what you do have is passion.
你关心公司  也关心公司的员工
You care about the company and the people that work there.
所以你要让他们理解你
That's what you have to get across to them.
要发自内心地说出你的想法
You got to speak from the heart.
费利西蒂
Felicity...
你愿意跟我一起吃晚饭吗
would you like to go out to dinner with me?
-我在说正事呢  奥利弗  -我也是
- I'm being serious here, Oliver. - So am I.
我是不是想多了
I don't want to read... too much into this,
你这是在约我出去吗
but are you asking me out on a date?
就像约会  真正的约会
Like an actual date? Like a... date-date?
我是说  跟你吃饭  就是...
Su--I mean, the implication being with dinner that you...
通常都是我  语不成句
Usually I'm the one talking in sentence fragments.
你愿意跟我一起吃晚饭吗
Would you like to go to dinner with me?
愿意
Yes.
凯文·尼科刚刚在一家酒铺行窃
Kelvin Nico just knocked over a liquor store.
尼科是斯蒂尔格雷夫的手下
Nico's in Steelgrave's crew.
把他的照片发给罗伊
Send his photo to Roy.
帮我接通费利西蒂
Get me Felicity.
没问题
You got it.
我现在不能打电话
I can't talk right now.
我在工作呢
I'm at work.
我能请你们稍等一会儿吗
Could I ask you guys just to wait one moment?
有人打电话来寻求技术支持
Someone's calling for tech support.
你让我被炒定鱿鱼了
Oh, you are going to get me so incredibly fired.
好吧  我黑进了市里的数据库
Okay, I am hacked into the city's database.
正在运行面部识别系统...好了
I am running facial recognition...now.
你喜欢意大利吗
Do you like Italian?
-什么  -今晚吃意大利菜
- What? - For tonight.
你喜欢吃意大利菜吧
You like Italian, right?
人人都爱意大利菜
Everyone likes Italian.
奥利弗  你正在高速追车呢
Oliver, you're in the middle of a high speed chase.
我可以一心多用
I'm multitasking.
找到他了  他在下水道里
I got him. He's in the sewer.
我在地下搜到了他的手机信号
I'm picking up his cell phone underneath.
他在格兰德路和埃姆斯路的转角处
He's at the corner of Grand and Ames.
还有  喜欢  我喜欢意大利菜
And yes, I love Italian.
兰斯警探...兰斯队长  也在追他
Detective Lance-- Captain Lance-- is also in pursuit.
不谢  我得走了
You are welcome. I have to go.
警长...谢谢你
Detective...thank you.
-那人是你搞定的  -谢谢你今天说的话
- You had it handled. - For what you said today.
我希望自己能做到更多
I wish I could do more.
你已经做得够多了
You've already done more than enough.
我得走了  得去个地方
I've got to go. Some place I have to be.
你是有个什么燃情约会吗
You got a hot date or something?
所以今天早上是你五个月以来
So this morning makes how many escape attempts
第几次试图逃跑了
in the last five months?
第九次
Nine.
我们现在的问题是不能互相理解
What we have here is a failure to reach an understanding.
去死吧
Go to hell.
这就是我把你从炼狱的海边救回来
So this is my reward from saving you from drowning
不让你溺死在那艘货船上的回报吗
in that freighter off the coast of Lian Yu?
没错
Yeah.
你为什么要救我
Why'd you do that?
你得明白这一点
That's need to know.
姑且说  我需要一个有你这种能力的人
Suffice it to say, I have need of a man of your capacity.
我不在乎
I don't care.
除了回家  我什么也不在乎
I don't care about anything except going home.
而你也应该清楚这一点
And you should know that.
你应该清楚
You should know
我不会停止逃跑的
that I will never stop trying to escape.
那你也应该知道
And you should know that
要杀一个全世界都以为他已经死了的人
it's extremely easy to kill someone
也是非常容易的
the world already thinks is dead.
那就杀了我吧
Kill me, then.
我不在乎
I don't care.
看来我们要换一种方式了
We're going to have to try this another way, then.
您好  谢谢您的耐心等候
Hi. Thank you for waiting.
没关系的  我就是想买这个
Ah, no problem. I just want to buy this.
这是一个TX40型号的卫星频率通讯器
This is a satellite frequency communicator TX40.
是的  我在试图突破
Yeah, I'm trying to breach
一个洋葱路由保护的防火墙
a TORsecured firewall
TOR: The Onion Router 洋葱头表层代理网络
然后需要找东西来帮我入侵
and I need something to help me piggyback off
一个锁眼"六角形"卫星  所以...
a Keyhole Hexagon satellite, so...
锁眼卫星: 间谍卫星
我这么干过一次
I did that once.
我黑过一个公共的无线网络信号
Hacked a public wi-fi signal,
用众包的潜行程序入侵的
piggybacked using crowd-sourced stealth processing.
你是费利西蒂·斯莫克
You're Felicity Smoak.
奎恩集团的前任员工
Formerly of Queen Consolidated.
介意我问一句吗  你为什么会在这里
Do you mind if I ask you something-- why are you here?
你怎么知道我是谁
How do you know who I am?
我认识一个人可能有兴趣
I know a guy who might be interested
雇一个有你这种专业技能的人
in hiring someone with your expertise.
实际上我现在并没有...
I'm not actually...
在找一份新工作  天呐
looking for a new job right now. God help me.
但是我能为您的这次购物服务
But I can help you buy this.
除非我不能  我的意思是  我不应该
Unless I can't. I mean, I shouldn't.
你不应该买这个
You shouldn't buy this.
好吧  显然你不明白
Ok. Clearly you don't understand
买卖销售到底是怎么一回事
how this whole sales thing works.
新一代的模型机  TX50型号的
The next-gen model, the TX50,
几个月之后就要问世了
comes out in a few months.
我去年见识到了一个
I got to touch one last year.
真是天赐之福
Pure bliss.
而且假如你想要攻破一个洋葱路由级别的安全系统
And if you want to breach TOR-level security,
你真的应该用一个远程管理工具
you should really deploy a remote administration tool.
我有个很好用的  这是链接
I have a good one. Here's the URL.
谢啦
Thanks.
黑客愉快
Happy hacking.
真希望如此
I certainly hope so.
是假警报
False alarm.
你确定吗  这些收缩...
Are you sure? These contractions...
只是假性宫缩
Just braxton-hicks.
你的宫口扩张连四厘米都不到
You're not even four centimeters dilated.
我觉得自己像一台M1-A1
I feel like an M1-A1.
是一种坦克
It's a tank.
想象一下一台很大很大的坦克
Think a big, big tank.
你进来住着是正确的选择
You did the right thing coming in.
你不希望你的丈夫...
You don't want your husband--
-男朋友  -前夫
- Boyfriend. - Ex-husband.
在高速公路旁给你接生吧
to be delivering the baby on the side of the freeway.
你现在可以把衣服穿上了
You can get dressed now.
好吧
All right.
你没事吧
Are you ok?
没事  我又不是那个怀胎九月的人
Yeah, yeah, I'm not the one that's nine months pregnant.
你看起来有点被吓到了
You look a little scared.
亲爱的  拜托  我打败过塔利班
Honey, please, I've thrown down with the Taliban,
马尔科姆·梅林  和一个
Malcolm Merlyn, and a host
使用了米拉库鲁技术的人体武器的组织
of Mirakuru-powered human weapons.
我很害怕
I'm terrified.
奎恩  两人桌
Queen, party of two.
这边请
Right this way.
-怎么了  -没事
- What? - Nothing.
-我只是有点...  -紧张
- I'm just- - Nervous?
是啊
Yeah.
想跟你约会的人可多着呢
Line forms behind me.
威士忌  不加冰
Scotch. Neat.
我只要水就好  谢谢
Just the water for me, thanks.
你  你确定吗
Are you--are you sure?
喝点酒也许有助于...
The booze might sort of help with the whole--
酒精跟我服用的三种药
The alcohol is not going
可能产生不良反应
to mix well with the three benzos I took.
我疯了吗
Am I being crazy?
我是说我们有什么好紧张的
I mean, what do we have to be nervous about?
我们已经说光了所有
Well, we've already exhausted every topic
通常应该在第一次约会时说的话题
that one would normally talk about on a first date.
还有第二次约会的话题  第三次的
And a second date and a third date,
其实所有约会的话题都说光了
and every date, actually,
我甚至见过你半身赤裸的样子
And I've already seen you shirtless.
见过好多次了
Multiple times.
半身赤裸  经常的事
Shirtless, all the time.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
我还有些事是你不知道的
There are still a few things that you don't know about me.
请吧  说一个
Please. Name one.
我离开的那五年
The five years that I was away...
我并不是一直待在炼狱岛
I wasn't always on Lian Yu.
我猜也是
I thought so.
你还去了哪
Where were you?
香港...
Hong Kong...
是其中之一
for one.
我最近总是在想...
And I have been thinking a lot recently about...
自己在那里的经历
my time there.
还有我不得不做出的那些选择
The choices that I had to make.
听起来那些年似乎发生了很多糟糕的事
Those years sound like they were full of a whole lot of suck.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我有点神游
I'm just a little out of my element.
我离开的那段时间
The entire time that I was gone,
我从来无法
I could never...
完全相信什么人
completely trust someone.
如果那种状态持续得太久了
And when that goes on for so long,
你就不会
you stop...
把人当做人看
seeing people for people.
而是当做
You see...
威胁
threats.
或目标
Or targets.
而我决定回家时  我...
And when I decided to come home, I...
我都不知道该如何摆脱那种思维方式了
I just didn't know how to turn that part of me off.
然后我走进了你的办公室
Then I walked into your office.
你竟是被我视作人的...
You were the first person that I could see as a...
第一个人
a person.
你身上有某种特质
There was just something about you.
是啊  我那时正咬着一根笔
Oh, yeah, I was chewing on a pen.
红色的笔
It was red.
卫星定位系统显示他就在那家餐厅
GPS shows him in the restaurant.
绿箭肯定就在那
The Arrow's definitely in there.
要想找到他  我们必须靠近些
If we're going to find him, we got to get in closer.
我们已经靠得够近了
We're close enough.
你还记得我告诉过你
Do you remember when I told you that
由于我们所做的这些事
because of what we do,
所以我觉得
I didn't think that
我不可能和某个...
I could be with someone that I...
自己真心在乎的人在一起
that I could really care about?
是的  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
也许我错了
So maybe I was wrong.
奥利弗  你...
Oliver, are you--
奥利弗
Olliver--
她还好吗
Is she ok?
她昏过去了
She's just knocked out.
新闻上都在播这个
Saw it all over the news,
警察和消防员都赶到现场了
police and fire are on the scene.
是啊  我觉得留在现场回答问题
Yeah, I didn't think it was the best idea
不是个好主意
to stick around and answer questions.
你认为你所在地方正好爆炸了
You don't think you and an explosion
是有人故意为之吗
at the same place is a coincidence?
看这个
Hey, check this out.
是个卫星定位器  在你外套里找到的
It's a GPS. I found it on your jacket.
不过已经坏了
It's wasted now.
你今晚稍早时干掉了斯蒂尔格雷夫手下的一个人
You took out one of Steelgrave's crew earlier tonight.
那是个圈套
It was a set up.
那样他们就可以往我身上放追踪器了
So they could plant that thing on me.
奥利弗  我知道你在想什么
Oliver, I know what you're thinking.
你不知道
No, you don't.
听着  我不是别人
Listen, I'm not other people.
我很清楚你在想什么  那种想法错了
I know exactly what's going on in your head, and you are wrong.
狄格尔  有人在我身上放追踪器
Diggle, somebody put a tracer on me
而我却没察觉
and I don't notice?
唯一的解释就是
The only explanation...
我的注意力被分散了
I lost my focus.
探长  我们稍早教训过的人
Detective. The person we took down earlier
和今晚为爆炸案负责的人是一伙的
is working with whoever's respoesible for tonight's explosion.
又是斯蒂尔格雷夫的人吧  我猜
Another one of Steelgrave's crew, I'm guessing.
我现在就想知道  那个组织的领导是谁
Well, I need to know who's at the top of that organization now.
哪里可以找到他
And where I can find him.
我这就查
I'm on it.
你安全了
You're safe.
没事了  有我在
You're safe. I'm here.
我和你是一边的
I'm on your side!
这件事我来搞定  探长
Got this handled, Detective.
那些人炸了一栋楼
These guys blew up a building.
你觉得我会袖手旁观吗
You think I'm sitting this out?
嫌犯叫维尔纳·赛托
Suspect's name is Werner Zytle.
他是个真正的疯子
He's a real nutmeg
那你自己小心行事
Keep your head on a swivel, then.
我叫维尔纳·赛托
I'm Werner Zytle.
但你也可以称我为"迷魂"
But you can call me Vertigo.
"伯爵"已经死了
The count's dead!
有些人永远也不会死
Some things never die.
比如说你
You, for example.
真是令人失望
It's frustrating.
也就是说我还得更努力点
Just means I have to try a little bit harder.
"伯爵"可能死了  这倒是真的
The count might be dead, true...
但是他那美妙的"迷魂"却流传了下来
But his glorious narcotic lives on--
而且还被改良了
with a few enhancements
它能让你看到你内心最大的恐惧
that will reveal to you your greatest fear.
就像是凝视着真相本身
Like gazing upon truth itself.
离他远点  不然你就死定了
Get away from him or get put down!
不  不
No...no!
费利西蒂  赶快叫救护车
Felicity, call an ambulance!
你没事吧
Are you ok?
维尔纳给你打的精神药物还挺强劲的
That was a pretty strong psychotropic Werner hit you with.
兰斯警探的情况怎么样了
How's Detective Lance's condition?
稳定下来了  他现在在星城总院
Stable. He's at Starling General.
我黑进了急救人员的无线通信
I hacked the paramedic radio.
他的冠状动脉痉挛用药可治愈
He had a coronary artery spasm treatable with medication.
他不会有事的
He'll be fine.
你怎么样
How are you?
信不信由你  我经历过更糟的初次约会
Believe it or not, I have had worse first dates.
去街上看看
Hit the streets.
维尔纳不会因为我而放弃他的计划的
Werner's agenda can't stop with me.
我要知道他在谋划什么
I need to know what he has planned.
这就去办
On it.
我去支援他
I'll back him up.
罗伊一个人可以的
Roy's got it.
回家陪莱拉吧
Go home to Lyla.
奥利弗
Oliver...
如果这和刚才发生的事有关的话
If this is about what happened, man,
冒险是工作的一部分
risk is part of the job.
狄格尔  现在只是情报收集
Diggle. It's just intel gathering.
罗伊可以处理
Roy can handle it.
我知道我们要好好谈谈
I know we need to talk.
谈谈我们的晚餐
About our dinner
还是我们那被人炸毁的晚餐
or our dinner getting blown up?
-两件事都要谈  -没事的
- Both. - It's ok.
抓到这人后  我们再谈
We'll talk about it after we catch this guy.
也许我们得重新安排开董事会的时间
But maybe we should reschedule the board meeting.
不到一小时会议就要开始了
It's in less than an hour.
我能出席的
I've got this.
请不要起来
你还没好呢
大家什么时候才会意识到我不会说中文
When are people going to realize that I don't speak Chinese?
这是日文
Japanese.
你会说英文
You speak English?
比你的中文说得好
Better than you speak Chinese.
我在哪里
Where am I?
在我们的家里
Our home.
我和我丈夫的家
Mine and my husband's.
你丈夫
Your husband?
欢迎来到我家
Welcome to my home.
吃晚饭吗
Dinner?
我得提醒你  医生说不能对我吼
I got to warn you, the doctors told me not to get yelled at.
那你不在乎医嘱
Well, it's a good thing you don't care about
还真是件好事
your doctor's instructions, then,
因为你还是继续执行外勤任务
since you're still going out in the field.
你知道什么是事先医疗指示吗
Do you know what an advanced health care directive is?
事先医疗指示  也被称为生前预嘱
那是你快死了的那次他们向我要的  爸
It's what they ask for when you're going to die, dad.
莎拉离开的那晚
The night Sara left,
你倒下的那晚
the night you collapsed,
急诊医生问我你是否有立过预嘱
the E.R. doctor asked me if you had one.
对不起  劳蕾尔  真的对不起
I'm sorry, Laurel, I really am.
对不起  宝贝
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
那你为什么一直这样逼自己
Then why do you keep pushing yourself like this?
我也不知道
I don't know how.
在你们姐们俩出生前我就已经是警察了
I've been a cop since before you and your sister were born.
我只知道这点
It's all I know.
如果我不是警察
If I'm not a cop...
那我还能是什么
what am I?
你是我的爸爸
You're my father.
我需要你
And I need you.
我刚和奈德·福斯特谈过
And I just spoke to Ned Foster.
他说董事会已经准备好了
He said the board is primed.
你只要走进去  令他们拍手称赞
You just have to go in there and wow them.
我很肯定这是商业术语
Which I am pretty sure is a business term.
恐怕我们发生了一点状况
I'm afraid we have a situation.
显然还有另一个投标人在竞投这家公司
Apparently there's another bidder for the company.
真的吗
Really?
是谁
Who?
我是雷·福斯特
Ray Palmer.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我很喜欢你的公司
Love your company.
很高兴再次见到你  斯莫克小姐
Nice to see you again, Miss Smoak.
你们俩认识吗
You two know each other?
抱歉我迟到了  交通堵塞
So sorry I am late. Heh, traffic was terrible.
所以我坐直升机来的
Which is why I took my helicopter.
停在你公司楼顶  希望你不介意
I parked on your roof. I hope that's ok.
你们会批准的吧
You guys validate, right?
见鬼的
Oh, frack.
两年前  星城的人们以为我死了
Two years ago, the people of Starling City thought I was dead.
但我回来了
I came back.
奎恩联合企业也一样能站起来
And so can Queen Consolidated.
伴随着星城国家银行的新投资
With Starling National Bank's new investment,
我们可以带领公司脱离破产管理  走向未来
we can take QC out of receivership and into the future.
这家公司是我的家人
I mean, this company's my family.
就像我母亲常说的...
And as my mother always said...
没有什么比家人更重要
there is nothing more important to me than family.
谢谢
Thank you.
很好的演讲
That was a good speech.
难以超越
Hard to top.
感谢大家今天的出席
Thank you all for coming out today.
我保证会言简意赅  不然先娱乐大家一下
I promise to be brief, if not a little entertaining.
那是其中一只我新出的智能手表
Ahh. Oh, that's one of my new smart watches.
对此我感到非常骄傲
I'm very proud of those.
你喜欢吗  对它的功能满意吗
You like it, it works for you?
好  总之  科学  数字
Yeah, good. Anyway. Science. Numbers.
我喜欢数字
I like numbers.
这些数字显示奎恩先生
These numbers show QC's performance
带领的公司绩效
under Mr. Queen's management.
我非常强调这点  顺便一提
I'm using that term extremely, BYW,
再顺便一提  这些数字
also BTW, these numbers
这不是华尔街上美化过的信息
aren't sanitized for Wall Street.
这是取自你们公司
This is raw information
服务器上的原始信息
from your company's own servers.
他怎么进去公司电脑的
How did he get into our computers?
在我看来他是使用了远程管理工具
Something tells me he deployed a remote administration tool.
但事实上
But the truth is,
这只是公司面临一个更大的问题的征兆
this company's woes are a symptom of a much larger problem.
那个问题就是星城
And that problem is Starling City.
如果星城继续衰退下去
Queen Consolidated can't hope to survive
奎恩联合企业就别想存活
if the city it's located in is dying.
猜怎么着  确实在衰退
Guess what? It is.
没人想继续住在这里
Nobody wants to live here anymore.
发生了两次恐怖袭击
And after two terrorist attacks,
不能怪他们不想留下
who can blame them?
这座城市仍然需要被拯救
This city still needs saving.
而那正是我对这家公司的愿景
And that is my vision for this company.
不止是让它从死灰中站起来
To not only see it rise from the ashes,
而是要带这座城市迈入新视野
but to take this city with it to that new horizon.
而那个新天地有个名字
And that new day has a name.
闪耀的星城
奥利弗
Oliver!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我以为会按我们所想的那样进行的
I really thought it was going to go our way.
我也是  但也许帕尔默博士会做得更好
So did I. But maybe the company's better off with Dr. Palmer.
去年我没时间管理奎恩联合企业
I couldn't make time for QC last year,
现在想拿回公司  是自私的
and trying to get the company back now, it's selfish.
那是以前的我会做的事
That's something that the old me would have done.
这半天提醒了我一件事
And if the past 12 hours have reminded me of anything,
就在两年前
it's that two years ago,
我决定放下奥利弗·奎恩的身份
I made the decision to put Oliver Queen aside
当绿箭  现在木已成舟
and be the Arrow. It's not a choice I get to unmake.
昨晚你在餐厅  不是那样想的
Last night at the restaurant, you didn't feel that way.
面对现实吧  费利西蒂
Look what happened, Felicity.
奥利弗  爆炸不是你的错
Oliver! The explosion wasn't your fault.
当维尔纳用"迷魂"飞镖攻击我时
When Werner hit me with the Vertigo dart,
他告诉我他的配方
he told me that his formula,
它会让我们看到我们最害怕的
it shows us our worst fear.
而我看到了自己
And I saw myself.
你不会真的以为你害怕自己吧
You don't really think you're afraid of yourself, do you?
我想我是害怕如果我继续当
I think I'm scared of what would happen
奥利弗·奎恩会发生什么事
if I let myself be Oliver Queen.
有什么线索
What did we find out?
你知道我们把星城的犯罪首领
You know how we've got the number of crime bosses
减少到只剩三个了吧
in Starling City down to three?
这个新来的的维尔纳  想弄到一个不剩
Well, this new guy, Werner, he wants to make it zero.
赢得比赛
Take out the competition.
米哈尔·佩托夫  卢西诺·科斯塔
Mikhail Petrov, Luciano Costa,
新川町下沢
Shintawa Shimosawa.
他们现在在哪里
What are their locations?
我找不到他们的最后已知地址
I'm not getting anything off of last known addresses.
维尔纳可能正在带走这些人
Werner could be moving these guys right now.
我在用最快速度查找了  这些人
I'm going as fast as I can! It's not like these guys
身上又不会带着定位器
walk around with little GPSs attached to them.
除非他们真的有带
Unless they do.
佩托夫  科斯塔  町下沢
Petrov, Costa, Shimosawa,
他们都在假释或保释
They're all on parole or out on bail.
假释
脚踝监控器
Ankle monitors.
不对劲  他们都在同一个地方
Can't be right. They're all in the same location.
火箭竞技场  今晚的重量级拳击冠军赛
Rockets Arena. The heavyweight title fight's tonight.
那可是犯罪首领的圣诞节
That's like christmas for crime bosses.
那里应该会聚集两万人
There'll be like 20,000 people there.
他为了拿下一个人  不惜炸掉一家餐馆
He was willing to blow up a restaurant to take down one man.
为了拿下三个人  他会炸掉一个体育场
He'll blow up a stadium to take down three.
火箭筒炸弹没有这种威力  你需要
Yeah, but an RPG won't do it. I need you looking
找出一个更大的爆炸装置
for a large explosive device.
罗伊...  着装
Roy... suit up.
你要我负责哪里
Where do you want me?
留在这里
Here.
我不能让你参加实战了
I can't have you in the field anymore.
真的吗  为什么
Really? What changed?
你快当父亲了
You're going to be a father.
奥利弗  五个月前
Oliver, you've known for
你就知道我要当父亲了
the past five months I was going to be a father.
所以我再问一遍
So I ask you again--
-哪里变了  -我变了
- What changed? - I have.
我顶的风险不能让你分担
My risks can't be your risks.
因为  狄格尔  你有正常的生活
That... Diggle, you have a life.
新的生活  而这
You have a new life, it's...
是我所不能有的
life I can't have.
我懂了
I get it.
你和费利西蒂遭遇了一场爆炸
You and Felicity were in an explosion.
死了人  你们俩也差点丧命
People died, either one of you could have.
但你们没有
But you didn't.
你不能因此动摇  哥们
You can't let that shake you, man.
兰斯探长现在正躺在医院里
Detective Lance is laying in hospital bed right now
-都是我害的  -你等等
- because I let him-- - Wait, wait, wait!
这是兰斯自己做的选择
Lance is his own man who makes his own decisions,
我也一样
and so am I.
这次不行
Not this one.
奥利弗  我这两年为你的事业出了不少力
Oliver, I've given the last two years of my life to your crusade.
我虽然不好说我挣得了什么
I don't know what that's supposed to earn me,
但最起码给了我自己做选择的资格
but it earns me at least the right to make my own choices.
-你错了  -去你的  奥利弗
- No, it doesn't-- - Damn it, Oliver,
要不是我你早死了十次八次了
you would be dead ten times over if it wasn't for me!
你说得对
You're right.
但这毕竟是我的事业
But this is my crusade,
所以也该我来决定
which makes this my decision.
定时器定了5分钟
It's a five minute timer.
来啊  你等什么呢
Come on! What are you waiting for?
等我同伴  讲
My partner. Go.
我分离出了一个与引爆器同频的电磁脉冲
I've isolated a frequency spike consistent with an incendiary device.
就在看台下方的维修通道内
It's in the maintenance tunnel underneath the stands.
炸弹交给我
I'll get the bomb.
你去抓这些混蛋
Get the son of a bitch.
还想来点吗
Back for more?
看这样子  你是对"迷魂"
It's as if you've developed an addiction
上瘾了啊
to Vertigo.
我已做了选择
I've made my choice.
费利西蒂  时间快到了
Felicity, we're running out of time here.
好  根据你的描述
Ok. From your description,
这炸弹的电路应该可以拆卸
it sounds like a collapsible circuit design.
费利西蒂
Felicity...
剪断黄线
Cut the yellow wire.
没有黄线
There is no yellow wire.
那好  换个办法
Ok, new plan.
看你头顶  那里应该布有隔热管道
Look above you, there should be insulated piping
连接竞技场的空调系统  管道内是氟利昂
pumping the arena's ac system. They're pumping freon.
截断一条管道  对准炸弹
You want to break one off, aim it at the bomb.
应该能把它冻住
You're going to freeze the thing.
不管用啊
It's not working!
别太吃惊啊
Don't look so surprised.
我还没走多久呢
I haven't been gone that long.
尽管把我关起来吧  无所谓了
Lock me down, it doesn't matter.
"迷魂"是剿不干净的
There will always be a Vertigo,
永远会有人接手这生意
always someone to pick up the mantle.
而这动力正是来自于你
You have given it the power.
你难道看不出来吗  看不明白吗
Don't you see? Don't you see?
-你气色不错  南达尔巴特怎么样  -热
- You look well. How's Nanda Parbat? - Hot.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
有人很想你
You've been missed.
我正要去看劳蕾尔  碰巧听见了你们的通讯
I was on my way to see Laurel, picked up your radio chattha.
你该转告费利西蒂  把通讯频道加加密
You should tell Felicity mix up her frequencies a bit.
好想法  你这次回来就不走了吗
That's a good tip. And is this permanent, you being back?
-我希望你别走  -再说
- I hope so. - We'll see.
你最近如何
How are you doing?
我  操心的事也不少
I'm... working through a few things.
给你个建议
Word of advice?
面具并不是我们的全部
We're not our masks.
我们的生活中也需要不戴面具的人
And we need people in our lives who don't wear one.
-你好啊  -你来这里干什么
- Hey. - What are you doing here?
你最好别是在跟踪我
And the answer better not be stalking me.
这得看你觉得定位你手机的卫星信号
Well, that depends on whether you consider
算不算跟踪了  好吧  我是在跟踪你
pinging your phone's GPS stalking. Ok, guilty.
但你知道我是怎么知道有人
But you know how I know a guy who would be interested
看中了你的专业技巧的吗
in hiring someone with your expertise?
没错  我还真用得上你的技术
Yeah, turns out I could really use it.
貌似有人黑了我的手机  我的笔记本
Seems somebody hacked my cell phone and my laptop
-还有桌面电脑  -哎呀  太糟了
- and my desktop. - Gee, that's too bad.
我所有的数据
All my data's been replaced
都被豪猪排气的音频文件换掉了
by audio files of porcupine flatulence.
所以我估计着这么做的人
And so I was hoping that whoever did it
没准乐意收了神通
might be willing to undo it
只要我为误导他们道个歉
if I apologized for misleading them in any way.
道个歉没准能行
That would probably work.
除非你误导他们
Oh, unless, of course, you did all that
只为了偷这个人的朋友的公司
to steal that person's friend's company,
这样的话  我建议你最好习惯习惯
in which case I would suggest getting used to the sound
啮齿类动物放屁的动静
of spiky rodents farting.
我什么都没偷嘛
I didn't steal anything!
好吧也许偷了点  但是到最后
Ok, maybe a little, but as it turns out,
我根本就没用上那些数据  你也听到演讲了
I didn't even need the data. I mean, you saw the speech.
很有说服力啊
It was a pretty good speech.
我的朋友刚刚当了父亲
My friends just had a baby,
如果你不介意的话
so if you don't mind,
我得去看望
there's another
另一个粘糊糊的小人儿[谄媚滑头]了
slimy little human that needs my attention.
对了  顺便一说
Oh, and BTW,
有空的时候也看看你的平板电脑
might want to check your tablet while you're at it.
她真是太可爱了
Oh, she is scrumptious!
恭喜你们啊  真心的
Mazel tov, guys, seriously.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可以以后再来
I can come back.
奥利弗  快进来
No, Oliver, come in.
她真是完美
Oh, she's perfect.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢你  奥利弗
Thank you, Oliver.
为什么谢我
For what?
因为你对了
For being right.
我看到她的那一刻
The second I looked at her...
一切都变了
everything changed.
整个宇宙  都变了
The whole universe... changed.
你说得对
You were right.
我要怎么才能出去
How do I get out of here?
你不能离开
You can't leave.
那你来阻止我啊
Well, why don't you try to stop me?
你知道我可以的
You've already learned I can.
你试过很多次了
Repeatedly.
阿曼达·沃勒想让你为她工作
Amanda Waller wants you working for her,
她会有自己的办法
and she will have her way.
那她太不幸了  我宁愿死
Yeah, well, too bad for her. I'd rather die.
所以她威胁的不是你的生命
Which is why it's not your life she's threatening.
我要对你负责
I am to be responsible for you.
她找到合适的方法激励我了
She's found the proper way to motivate me.
绍夫
Akio.
她威胁了我的家人
She's threatened my family.
我放你走的话她会杀了他们
She'll kill them if I let you go.
我父亲生前喜欢一句谚语
My father had a proverb he was once fond of.
一人不能生有两名
A man cannot live by two names.
什么意思
And what does that mean?
放在你身上...
In your case...
意思就是你别无选择
I believe it means not having any choice.
他们看上去真的很幸福
They look really happy.
-她真漂亮  -是啊
- She's beautiful. - She is.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
我不想跟你谈
I don't want to talk.
虽然对我来说  这是第一次
Which for me, I know, is a little unprecedented.
但是
But...
只要我们谈了  就结束了
as soon as we talk, it's over.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我以为我可以做自己
I thought that I could be me
同时做绿箭
and the Arrow...
但是我做不到
But I can't.
现在还做不到
Not now.
-可能永远都做不到  -那就明确跟我说
- Maybe not ever. - Then say never.
不要  再模棱两可了
Stop... dangling maybes.
你明确跟我说我们俩之间不可能
Say it's never going to work out between us.
-说你从没爱过我...  -费利西蒂
- Say you never loved me, say you-- - Felicity...
不要让我说不爱你
Don't ask me to say that I don't love you.
我说过  只要我们谈了...
I told you as soon as we talked...
我们就结束了
it would be over.
喂
Hello?
我是巴里
It's Barry.
巴里·阿伦
Barry Allen.
我醒了
I woke up.
我需要你给我些建议
I could use some advice.
我马上去找你
I'll be right there.
我还以为你把
And here I thought that you used up
刺客联盟度假时间都用完了
all of your league of assassin vacation days.
你气色不错  爸爸怎么样
You look great. How's dad doing?
老样子
The same.
见到你应该会好点
Seeing you will help.
我不想让他知道我来了
I don't want him to know I'm in town,
至少现在还不想
not just yet.
你是不想让他知道你来了
You don't want him to know you're in town,
还是不想让他知道你来的原因
or you don't want him to know why?
两者都不想
Both.
这种生活...
This life, it...
真的很复杂
it's complicated.
我们不想让你作出选择
We didn't want you to choose it.
不要为了我们去选择
Not for us.
我知道  我是为了自己
I know. I chose it for me.
绿箭...
The Arrow--
奥利弗
Oliver--
抓住了一个想炸毁火箭竞技场的人
busted someone who tried to blow up Rockets Arena.
我老板让我去局里
And my boss wants me to head to the station
帮忙一起审讯
to backstop the interrogation.
劳蕾尔·兰斯
Laurel Lance.
一直在努力拯救世界
Always trying to save the world.
家族遗传
Runs in the family.
爱你
Love you.
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
不不  莎拉
Oh! No! No! Sara!
莎拉  不  不要
Sara! No, no!
绿箭